<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on Zheng Wang</title>
    <link>https://zwang4.github.io/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on Zheng Wang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zwang4.github.io/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zwang4.github.io/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zwang4.github.io/home/about/</guid>
      <description>I work to make software development easier and more accessible so that every programmer can easily write, maintain and optimise software. I maintain a list of must-read research papers for machine learning in compilers. I am interested in solving real-world problems by building working prototypes to be tested in real-life environments and real computing hardware using realistic workloads. I lead the Intelligent Systems Software Lab. My research interests include:
 Program optimisation and analysis: I am interested in how we can design new algorithms and optimisation techniques at compilers and operating systems to improve application performance and energy efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>https://zwang4.github.io/home/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zwang4.github.io/home/news/</guid>
      <description>[Jan, 2025] PROM received a distingusished paper award at CGO 2025 [Oct, 2024] Congratulations to Xiaoyang and Huanting winning the AI SuperConnector Award; Each is given a £20K seed fund to commercialise their research. [March, 2024] Received CGO 2024 Test-of-time Award for my CGO&amp;rsquo;13 paper; selected as a paper that was published 10 &amp;ndash; 12 years prior and has had a lasting impact on the field. [September, 2023] New 24-month Innovative UK project awarded (PI) - An RA post will open soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Team</title>
      <link>https://zwang4.github.io/home/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zwang4.github.io/home/team/</guid>
      <description>For more information, see the group page.
Research Fellows  Xiaoyang Sun Jingzhi Gong - KTP Associate with TurinTech Huanting Wang  PhD Students  Yachao Zhu, 04 / 2021 - (Funded by PhD Scholarship); Patrick Lenihan, 10 / 2021 - (Funded by School of Computing DTP Scholarship); Beite Yang, 10 / 2021 - (co-supervised with Amirul Khan and Peter Jimack); Yiming Ma, 09 / 2023 - (Funded by Industry PhD scholarship); Hua Wei Zhang, 10 / 2023 - (Funded by DTP scholarship); Ce Yang, 10 / 2023 - Xiao Qin, 10 / 2024 - Yucheol Choi, 03 / 2025 - Yassine Marzouk, 10 / 2025 - (Funded by DLA Case studentship);  Research Assistants and Software Engineers  Yuhang Wu JInyi Fan  Alumni  Huanting Wang, 10 / 2021 - 09 / 2025 - now Research Fellow at University of Leeds Ying Wu, 01 / 2021 - 09 / 2025 - now Assistant Professor at Fujian Agriculture and Forestry University Shenghao Qiu, 10 / 2020 - 09 / 2025 - now Research Fellow in University of York Jiayu Zhao, 10 / 2020 - 05 / 2025 - now with Huawei Cambridge Lab Chunwei Xia 05 / 2023 - 09 / 2024 - now Lecturer at University of Leeds Xiaoyang Sun 10 / 2019 - 11 / 2023 - now Research Fellow at University of Leeds Yiming Wang Visiting PhD Student 2023 - 2024 Rodrigo Caetano Rocha 10 / 2016 - 07 / 2021 - now Senior Researcher at Huawei Edinburgh Lab Ben Taylor (PhD Student) - firt job: Transport for the North Vicent Sanz Marco (PDRA) - Assistant professor at Osaka University, Japan Volker Seeker (PDRA) - now with Meta AI Guixin Ye - now associate professor; Best paper award nomination at CCS 2018, ACM China Best PhD Dissertation Award (Shaanxi Province).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awards and Recognition</title>
      <link>https://zwang4.github.io/home/awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zwang4.github.io/home/awards/</guid>
      <description>CGO 2025 Distinguished Paper Award CGO 2024 Test-of-Time Award Named among Standford World&amp;rsquo;s Top 2% Scientists 2020, 2021, 2022, 2023, 2024 Facebook research award, 2021 Best Paper Award: ACM/IEEE PACT 2010, ACM/IEEE CGO 2017, ACM/IEEE PACT 2017, ACM/IEEE CGO 2019 Best Paper Nomination: ACM SC 2023, ACM CCS 2018, ACM SenSys 2019 Best Presentation Award: ACM/IEEE PACT 2010, ACM/IEEE CGO 2013 HiPEAC Paper Award: ASPLOS 2024, PLDI 2021, PLDI 2020, PLDI 2009 - for &amp;ldquo;publishing their work at conferences in which Europe is not strongly represented&amp;rdquo; IBM Bravo!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Publications</title>
      <link>https://zwang4.github.io/home/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zwang4.github.io/home/publications/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selected Publications</title>
      <link>https://zwang4.github.io/home/publications_selected/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zwang4.github.io/home/publications_selected/</guid>
      <description>Google Scholar | Completed List @ Lancaster University Publication Portal | DBLP</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Services</title>
      <link>https://zwang4.github.io/home/services/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zwang4.github.io/home/services/</guid>
      <description> Professional Services  Guest editor: Elesiver Journal of Computer Languages, CCF Transactions on High Performance Computing Program/General Chair: ICAC 2025, ICAC 2024, COSMIC 2019 @ CGO 2019, COSMIC 2017 @ CGO 2017, COSMIC 2015 @ CGO 2015, COSMIC 2013 @ CGO 2013, HiPEAC Thematic Session 2013 and 2016 Artifact Evaluation Chair: PACT 2016 Track co-chair: WWW 2026 - The ACM Web Conference 2026 Workshop co-chair: Mobisys 23 Lightning Talk Chair: PLDI 2017 Program Committee Member: AAAI 2026 (Senior PC)， ISCA 2025, IPDPS 25-26, 19-23, CGO 24-26, 22, 20, PPoPP 25, 20, CCGRID 25, COLING 25, 18, IJCAI 19-26 (area chair), ACM Student Research Competition at CGO 24, DAC 24, ISSTA 2024, EuroMLSys 22-24, AccML 24, 23, AACL 23, 22, 20, ACL 23, 19, LCTES 23, 21, EMNLP 22, 21, HIPS 22, AAAI 22, MLSH 20 @ PACT 20, IEEE TPDS Special Section on Parallel and Distributed Computing Techniques for AI, ML and DL 2020, Challenge 20, NPC 19, Aorta @ ECOOP 19, ICAC 19, PACT 18, NPC 18, ICPADS 18, INFOCOMP 18, ICAC 18, ParCo 17, CC 16, ERPP 15, ML4PL 15, ParCo 15, ICPP-EMS 15, PASA 14, PASA 13, ITCS 12, ITCS 11, ICPADS 09 External Review Committee Member: CGO 2018, CGO 2015, PLDI 2014, HPCA 2015, HiPEAC 2011  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Projects</title>
      <link>https://zwang4.github.io/home/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zwang4.github.io/home/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://zwang4.github.io/home/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zwang4.github.io/home/teaching/</guid>
      <description> Teaching  XJCO1211 Computer Architecture, 2023- XJCO1921 Programming Project, 2021-  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biography</title>
      <link>https://zwang4.github.io/home/bio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zwang4.github.io/home/bio/</guid>
      <description> July 2019 - , Professor (Associate Professor prior 2022) School of Computing, University of Leeds September 2013 - July 2019, Senior Lecturer (Lecturer prior 2017), School of Computing and Communications, Lancaster University. 2012 - 2013, Research Associate, the University of Edinbugh. 2007 - 2011, PhD Student, the University of Edinburgh. Nominated for BCS Distinguished Dissertation Award; 2005 - 2007, Research Staff member, IBM China Research Lab  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://zwang4.github.io/home/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zwang4.github.io/home/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>